[Respect Copyright, Everyone's Responsibility]
[정품을 보호하는 것은 우리 모두의 책임입니다]
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설 '천향인' 각색 작품]
[Episode 9]
[제9화]
Using such expensive travel talismans just to transport wine?
이리 귀한 질행부를 술 배달에 쓰시다니
His Majesty's Duantu Nectar is finally here.
황형께서 보내신 단도옥액이 마침내 당도했구나
Why send wine all this way?
이 먼 곳까지 술은 어찌하여 보내셨답니까?
How can the Mid-Autumn Festival be without wine?
중추 가절에 술이 빠져서야 되겠느냐?
- Mid-Autumn Festival? - Mid-Autumn Festival?
중추라
Smells good, right?
향기롭지 않으냐?
So many mooncakes.
월병이 이리도 많다니
Lifei!
려비 낭자
Changyue specially picked these from Qingqiu.
이것들은 모두 언니께서 주변 환경에 맞춰
They are tailored to local flavors.
특별히 청구에서 채집해 오신 것들이랍니다.
Five-nut filling made with vanilla, nectar, wild jujube,
향초와 꽃꿀, 멧대추는 물론이고
and dried grass stems.
말린 풀줄기로 만든 오인소까지 있지요
Once Ye and Tongzhou get back from shopping,
오라버니와 동주 도령께서 장을 보아 돌아오시면
we can dig in.
바로 먹을 수 있답니다
My master was stingy back then.
예전에 우리 사부님은 어찌나 구두쇠셨던지
He never wanted to spend money buying me mooncakes.
돈이 아깝다고 제게 월병 한번을 안 사주셨답니다
Always fobbed me off with potato cakes
맨날 감자전이나 무 한 조각 같은 걸로
and radish slices.
대충 때우려고 하셨다니까요
Here.
자
What should I grab for you?
제가 무엇을 거들어 드릴까요?
That one.
저거요
- This one? - Yeah.
-이거요? -맞습니다
Put it in?
안에 넣을까요?
A bit more.
조금만 더요
More?
조금만 더 넣으셔요
Enough?
이만하면 됩니까?
That's enough.
족합니다
Okay.
좋습니다
If only Shanhua were here.
형님께서도 이곳에 계셨다면 얼마나 좋았을꼬
Smells so good.
향이 참으로 좋군요
This one.
이것 좀 보세요
Changyue.
언니
What are you doing?
왜 그러느냐?
Are you missing Lu?
형님이 그리운 거야?
I get it.
그 마음 안다
Festivals always make you miss your loved ones.
'좋은 날이 오면 그리운 이가 더 생각난다'고 하잖느냐
I miss my master too.
나 역시 사부님이 보고 싶구나
That old man would probably
그 영감탱이가 여기 있었다면
be humming a little tune if he were here.
신이 나서 콧노래를 흥얼거렸을 텐데 말이지
They'll all be here someday.
훗날에는, 훗날에는 필시 모두 함께 모일 수 있을 게야
For sure.
틀림없이 그리될 게다
But we should still enjoy ourselves this time.
허니 이번 명절도 우리는 즐겁게 보내야 마땅하지 않겠느냐
Let's go make mooncakes.
가자, 월병을 만들러 가자꾸나
Come on.
가자
Let's go. Come on.
가자니까,얼른
Hurry.
빨리 오려무나
Here.
자
You're on prep duty.
네가 옆에서 거들어다오
Here, Changyue.
자,언니
Why isn't Lifei out yet?
려비낭자는 어찌 아직도 나오지 게지?
Here.
받으려무나
Thanks, Changyue.
감사합니다,언니
Is it tasty?
맛이 좋으냐?
First, a toast to Xiuyuan's recovery.
우선 수원의 쾌유를 기념하며 한 잔 비웁시다
And then to us driving Zong Quan away!
그다음에는 우리가 종권을 격퇴한 것을 축하하는 걸로 하지요
Cheers!
건배
Yes!
좋습니다
Oh, Lifei,
맞다, 려비 낭자
you never told us
아직 고하지 않은 게 있지 않습니까?
how Zong Quan finally left.
그 종권이라는 자는 결국 어떻게 가 버렸습니까?
That was all thanks to our formation's power.
그야 당연히 우리의 진법이 위력을 발휘한 덕이지요
Besides,
게다가
if he stayed, he would've been caught by the masters.
도망치지 않고 버티다간 선생들께 발각될까 두려웠을 테지요
You just recovered. You can't drink.
이제 막 부상에서 회복했거늘, 어찌 술을 입에 대느냐?
I...
나
Let me drink for you.
그럼 너도 조금만 들거라
Ye, Changyue.
엽 오라버니, 언니
Looks like we'll have to drink more.
아무래도 저희가 더 많이 마셔야겠습니다
You're keeping such good wine to yourselves.
이렇게 좋은 술을 그대들끼리만 즐기려는 것입니까?
- Give it to me. - No!
- 이리 주십시오 - 아니 됩니다
You can't drink.
술을 입에 대셔서는 안 됩니다
Why can't I?
어찌하여 저는 술을 마실 수 없다는 것입니까?
Changyue, let's have more.
언니, 저희가 더 많이 마셔요
Give it to me.
이리 주십시오,이리 주십시오
You can't have it.
술을 입에 대셔서는 안 됩니다,술을 입에 대셔서는 안 됩니다
Just a little.
조금만 주십시오
Just pour me one cup.
제발 한 잔만 따라 주십시오
One cup, alright?
딱 한 잔만 마시면 안 되겠습니까?
So beautiful.
참으로 아름답구나
Hey,
그대들에게만 알려 드리는 비밀인데
they say making a wish to the moon really works.
달을 향해 소원을 빌면 반드시 이루어진다 하더군요
They'll
그러면 나중에
deliver your wish paper to the moon.
이 소원지를 달님께 보낸다고 합니다
Let's write ours first.
우리도 어서 먼저 적어 봅시다
Really?
정말이냐?
For real. Try it.
정말이고말고요, 한번 적어 보시지요
Just try.
해 보세요
"May we be together forever."
오직 바라는 것은, 그리운 이와 오래도록 함께하는 것
"The same every year."
해마다 매번 오늘만 같기를 바랍니다
You two even wrote the same wish.
두 분은 어찌 소원까지 이리 똑같으십니까
What did you write?
너는 무엇이라 적었느냐?
It's a secret.
비밀입니다
[Lucky]
[길]
Don't worry.
염려 마
Lu's bound to have good luck
노 오라버니께서는 필시 대길하실 것이니
and a long life.
백세까지 천수를 누리실 게야
Once you're fully healed,
네 부상이 완쾌되거든
we'll go to Xingzheng Hall together.
우리 함께 성정관으로 가자꾸나
Together?
우리 말이냐?
Together.
그래, 함께 가는 게야
We'll take on Zhenyunzi together.
그리하여 그 진운자라는 자를 함께 상대하는 거지
We're no match for him.
우리는 그의 적수가 되지 못한다
Xuanshanzi is an elder of Xingzheng Hall.
내 백부는 바로 성정관의 장로이시네
If he helps,
만일 백부께서 힘을 보태 주시겠다면
maybe we can force Zhenyunzi to release Lu.
어쩌면 진운자를 압박해 사람을 데려올 수 있을지도 모르지
No.
안 되오
That'd drag you all into it.
그대들에게 누를 끼치게 될 것이오
What are you saying?
누라니, 무슨 당치 않은 소리냐
You can't always be a lone ranger in this world.
사람이 세상을 살아가며 어찌 매번 홀로 오고 갈 수 있겠느냐
It's good to have people
곁에 의지할 사람이 있고, 힘을 보탤 이가 있다는 건
you can lean on.
참으로 좋은 일이지
If we help each other,
네가 나를 돕고 내가 너를 돕다 보면
we can get through anything.
이 세상에 넘지 못할 고비가 어디 있겠느냐?
Right. Lifei's right.
맞다, 려비의 말이 백번 옳아
Lifei,
려비야
why haven't you written yours yet?
너는 어찌 아직도 적지 않는 게냐?
Me?
저는...
I...
저는 말입니다
What's that?
이것은 무엇이냐?
It means reunion.
단란함과 원만함을 그린 것이지요
I hope I find my master soon.
제 소원은 하루빨리 사부님을 찾는 것이고
I hope Xiuyuan
또한 수원이가
reunites with Lu soon.
속히 형님과 상봉하는 것이며
And I hope you get everything you wish for.
그대 또한 뜻하는 바를 원만히 이루는 것입니다
What are you three whispering about?
세 분께서 무슨 이야기를 나누고 계십니까?
You get your wishes, but what about us?
무슨 뜻을 이루길 바란다고 하시니 그렇다면 저희는 어찌 되는 것입니까?
Our hearts are as one.
당연히 마음과 마음이 서로 통하는 사이이니
We'll never part.
영원히 헤어지지 않는 것이죠
Quick, make your wish!
어서, 소원을 올립시다
Come on.
어서요
Here.
자
Aim it over there.
저쪽을 향해서 올립시다
Hangover pill. Take it.
숙취환이니, 드셔보세요
I haven't seen you this happy
고로국을 떠나온 이래로
since we left Gaolu.
이토록 안색이 밝으신 모습은 실로 오랜만에 뵙습니다
I made this. For you.
새로 엮은 것이니, 받거라
I already have plenty.
제게는 이미 차고 넘칩니다
Give this one to Gelin.
이것은 가림에게 주세요
Do you remember when I first gave you
내가 네게 처음으로 여치 장난감을
a grasshopper?
만들어 주던 날을 기억하고 있느냐?
It's been eleven years already.
눈 깜짝할 사이에 어느덧 십일 년이 흘렀구나
Changyue,
창월아
let me take care of you from now on.
남은 생은, 내가 널 보살피며 살게 해다오
You're the Crown Prince.
오라버니께서는 태자이십니다
The Baili family has always been loyal to the Gaolu imperial family.
백리 가문은 대대로 고로 황실에 충성을 바쳐 왔습니다
I don't want your loyalty. I want your...
내겐  네 충성 따위는 필요 없다, 내가 원하는 건 오직 너다
Enough, Ye!
그만하세요, 엽 오라버니
You'll always be my and Gelin's
오라버니는 영원히 저와 가림에게
beloved cousin.
공경하고 아끼는 오라버니이십니다
Cousin?
오라버니라니...
It's getting late. You should head back and rest.
밤이 깊었으니, 이만 처소로 드시어 쉬십시오
You only see me as a cousin?
정녕 나를 오라비로만 여기는 게냐?
Can't you see
정녕 내 가슴에 품은
how I feel about you?
이 연모의 정이 보이지 않는단 말이냐?
It's because of Gelin, isn't it?
가림 때문이냐? 그런 것이냐?
Is it because of Gelin?
가림 때문인 게냐?
Is it because you care about Gelin?
말해 보거라,정녕 가림이 마음에 걸리는 것이냐?
You're drunk.
취하셨습니다
- Is it because of Gelin? -Don't say anymore...
-정녕 가림 때문인 것이냐?-그만하세요
Changyue!
창월아
It doesn't matter.
다 상관없다
None of it matters.
그 어떤 것도 내겐 중요치 않아
Only you matter to me.
오직 너만이 내게 소중할 뿐이다
Xiaobangchui.
소봉추
Xiuyuan.
수원아
Lifei, you're drunk.
려비야, 네가 취했구나
Get some sleep.
어서 잠자리에 들거라
♪Our fates intertwined, embracing yet fighting♪
♪얽히고설킨 숙명 속에 서로를 품고 스러지니♪
Xiuyuan.
수원아
♪The hardest bond to balance♪
♪이보다 애달픈 연이 어디 있으랴♪
You're really good-looking.
너는 참으로 곱구나
I've never seen you smile.
헌데 네 웃는 얼굴은 여태 한 번도 모지 못했구나
Give me a smile.
한 번만 웃어보거라
♪Love sprouts again in this lifetime♪
♪이번 생의 애달픈사랑은 다시 움트네♪
♪No calamity can rival♪
♪수많은 겁난을 겪어도♪
♪The lingering thread of a fragrance♪
♪ 한 줄기 향기를 향한 미련은 떨치지 못하네♪
Come on, smile.
한 번만 웃어보래도
Smile.
웃어보거라
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너 부도탑을 지나 ♪
Stop it.
장난치지 말거라
I...
나...
You always look
너는 평소에도
so troubled.
늘 근심 어린 낯빛뿐이어서
I've never seen you genuinely smile.
진심으로 웃는 모습을 한 번도 본 적이 없구나
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
Smile.
웃어보거라
♪With you, we melt into mist and haze♪
♪그대와 함께 신기루가 되리라♪
If you don't smile,
오늘 내 앞에서 웃어주지 않는다면
I'm not letting you go.
결코 너를 보내주지 않을 것이다
♪I trade the highest heaven and endless clouds♪
♪내 구천을 밟고 만 리의 운하를 지나♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Pierced by countless arrows, pain and illness pile on♪
♪만 개의 화살이 심장을 꿰뚫는 고통이 밀려와도♪
♪Yet I remain silent♪
♪그저 묵묵히 소리 없이 삼키네♪
♪Deep love and long yearning, a kiss falls into a dream♪
♪깊어가는 정과 그리움은 꿈결 속에 내려앉고♪
♪In the distant night, bitterness blooms♪
♪외롭고 긴 밤하늘 아래 쓰라린 꽃이 피어나네♪
♪The grand chapter is rewritten♪
♪찬란한 운명을 다시 쓰니♪
♪Startling the whole world♪
♪온 세상이 경탄하누나♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
So you can bite me, but I can't bite you?
너만 날 물고, 나는 너를 물지도 못한단 말이냐?
Since I bit you,
이리 내게 물렸으니
you're mine from now on.
이제부터 너는 내 사람이니라
♪Comes that one moment of defiance♪
♪끝까지 모질게 버텨내던 그 순간♪
♪In the human world or above, like flowing water♪
♪천상과 인간 세상사 모두 흐르는 물과 ♪
♪And falling petals♪
♪지는 꽃 같으니♪
♪Let this fleeting life be whatever it may♪
♪덧없는 이 허무한 삶을 그저 순리에 맡기리라♪
Shanhua.
형님
Lei Xiuyuan.
뇌수원
- Shanhua! - Shanhua's on the verge of death.
-형님 - 산화의 목숨이 경각에 달렸으니
Come see him one last time.
지체 말고 와서 그의 마지막 얼굴을 보거라
His life is in your hands.
그의 생사는 네 손에 달려 있다
Know that.
그리 알거라
Lime powder. Escape talismans.
석회 가루에 돈지부까지
All set.
준비는 다 끝났다
Zhenyunzi is threatening you
진운자가 네 형님의 목숨을 빌미로
with Lu's life.
너를 협박하고 있거늘
And you're going alone? Walking to your death?
홀로 가겠다는 것이냐? 제 발로 사지로 걸어 들어가겠다는 것이냐?
How did you know?
그대들은 어찌 이를 알았소?
I overheard it when I woke up last night.
어젯밤 술에서 깨어났을 때 우연히 듣게 되었네
Xiuyuan, you should've told us
수원아,이리 중차대한 일이라면
about this.
마땅히 우리에게  알렸어야지
Zhenyunzi's cultivation is even stronger than Zong Quan's.
진운자의 법력은 종권보다 한 수 위라
This trip is practically suicide.
이번 길은 구사일생이 될 터인데
You don't have to risk yourselves for me.
나 때문에 그대들까지 험로에 들게 할 수는 없소
A real friend isn't afraid of that!
죽음이 두렵다면 애당초 의형제라 할 수 없지
Let's go together. Saving him is what matters.
함께 가자,사람을 구하는 일이 급하네
Enough with the chatter.
쓸데없는 말은 그만하라
Yeah.
그러게
When we formed the Fragrance Bond, we swore to
우리가 천향인의 결의를 맺을 때
live and die together.
이미 생사를 함께하기로 약조하지 않았더냐
A man of honor keeps his word.
군자의 한 번의 약속을 어찌 어길 수 있겠느냐
Once I save Shanhua,
내 형님을 구해낸 뒤
I'll repay you.
반드시 그대들에게 두둑이 보답하겠네
Let's move!
출발하세
None of you
어찌하여 다들 하나같이
says anything to my face.
속 시원히 마주 보고 말씀하지 않으십니까
Always hiding things and making me worry.
꼭 이리 숨기고 감추어 사람을 걱정하게 하셔야만 했습니까?
Gelin, actually...
가림아,실은
Whatever you want to do, just go do it.
그대들이 하고 싶은 대로 하시면 됩니다
If you're happy, I'm happy.
그대들이 즐겁다면 저 또한 그것으로 족합니다
Alright. Let's head back to the academy.
자,이제 서원으로 돌아갑시다
Gelin! Gelin!
가림아,가림아
Gelin!
가림아
Your Highness.
소왕야
Your Highness, the master has been waiting.
영왕전하, 사존께서 기다리신 지 오래되었습니다
Please, come in.
어서 드시지요
After you.
사형, 드시지요
Why are you here? And dressed like that?
어찌하여 여기까지 온 것이냐? 옷차림은 또 왜 그 모양이고
The academy doesn't pay us.
서원에서는 녹봉을 주지 않으니
I can't just burn through my savings.
가산만 축내고 있을 수는 없지 않더냐
Need to find a side job.
이렇게 품을 팔아 푼돈이라도 벌어야지
What's wrong?
왜 그러느냐?
When I came over,
방금 이곳에  당도할 때
I noticed a pavilion with strong spirit energy
어느 전각 하나에만 영력이 유독 짙은 것을 보았어
and a barrier around it.
게다가 그곳에는 결계까지 쳐져 있더구나
Maybe it's Zhenyunzi's place.
내 짐작으로는 진운자의 거처가 틀림없어
I want to check it out.
한번 가서 살펴볼 생각이야
Then I'm coming with you.
그렇다면 나도 동행하마
No. This is an immortal sect.
안돼, 안 돼, 이곳은 선문이야
And too many people will alert him.
같이 움직였다간 도리어 적의 경계심만 살 뿐이야
You said it yourself, this is an immortal sect.
자네도 말하지 않았나, 이곳은 선문이라고
Zhenyunzi has deep cultivation.
진운자는 법력이 워낙 고강하니
If I don't draw him away,
내가 그를 다른 곳으로 유인하지 않으면
you'll definitely get caught.
반드시 들키고 말 것이야
I have a way
내게 한 가지 묘책이 있소
to lure Zhenyunzi out.
진운자를 밖으로 유인해 낼 계책이지
This is the layout of Xingzheng Hall's barriers.
이것은 성정관 곳곳에 설치된 결계의 배치도네
Be careful when you move around.
움직일 때는 각별히 조심하게
Don't trigger anything.
금기를 건드려서는 절대 안 되네
Zhenyunzi is very cunning.
진운자는 가히 늙은 여우와 같은 자입니다
How are you going to draw him out?
대체 어찌 그를 유인하실 생각이십니까?
Persuade Xuanshanzi to host a banquet for Zhenyunzi
백부를 설득하여, 진운자를 위한 연회를 베풀게 할 것이야
and test his defenses.
그 자리에서 그의 속내를 떠보려 하네
After repeated inspections, the academy masters
서원의 선생님들께서 재삼 정밀히 감정하신 끝에
determined that dark stone
그 해외에서 온 흑석이
was just a piece from Divine Tree Island.
건목도의 도석임을 밝혀내셨습니다
But Zong Quan won't let it go.
허나 종권은 끝내 포기하지 않고
He keeps hunting for the Divine Tree.
기어이 건목의 행방을 추적하려 하였습니다
Knowing my identity,
내 신분을 뻔히 알면서도
he still tried to kill me.
뒤에서 암수를 꾸미다니
He clearly has no regard for the Yue State
이는 애당초 우리 월국과 성정관을
or Xingzheng Hall.
안중에도 두지 않았다는 증좌입니다
Your Highness, is this why
영왕 전하, 본좌를 이곳으로 청해 들인 이유가
you invited me over?
고작 이걸 논하기 위함이었소?
Sir, I've learned that the Divine Tree's power is immense
선배, 건목의 영력이 실로 막대하다는 말을 들었습니다
and not for one person alone.
그런 신물은 한 사람이 독차지할 수 있는 것이 아니지요
Why don't we join forces to find it and share what we gain?
차라리 힘을 합쳐 함께 찾아 서로 뜻을 나누는 것이 어떻겠습니까?
Once we find the Divine Tree, we can elevate Xingzheng Hall.
건목을 찾게 되면 성정관을 더욱 융성하게 하고
Don't let Longming Sanctuary seize the opportunity.
용명좌에게는 틈탈 기회조차 주지 말아야 하지 않겠습니까
Xuanshanzi, what do you think?
사형의 의향은 어떠하십니까?
A catastrophe is coming. We should set aside our differences,
대재앙이 머지않았으니,우리 동문은 지난 원한을 접어 두고
find the Divine Tree, and stand against the Sea Calamity together.
힘을 합쳐 건목을 찾아 함께 해운을 막아야 하네
That guard looks unfamiliar.
헌데, 저 시위는 낯이 다소 설구려
With Tongzhou's appearance-changing pill,
동주의 환연단으로 기운을 가렸으니
that old guy shouldn't recognize me.
저 늙은 여우가 날 알아보진 못하겠지?
Zhurong Stone?
축융석이 아닌가
Xuanshanzi, why would you pass down
사형, 성정관의 보물
Xingzheng Hall's supreme treasure
어찌 아직 입문도 하지 않은 새파란 후배에게 물려주신 겁니까?
Xingzheng Hall was founded by the Ji clan's ancestors
본래 성정관은 기씨 선조들께서 세우신 곳이고
and has been supported by the Yue State for centuries.
수백 년간 월국의 공봉을 받아오지 않았느냐
Tongzhou has long been recorded as my disciple.
동주는 이미 오래전에 내 문하로 거두었네
Sir, you attacked my guard.
선배님, 제 시위를 기습하시다니
What do you want?
대체 무슨 속셈이십니까?
Her spirit power is masked.
저 자의 영력이 가려진 것을 보니
She's taken an appearance-changing pill.
분명 환연단을 복용한 것이 틀림없소
I just wanted to
본좌는 그저
see her true face.
이 시위의 진면목을 확인하고 싶었을 뿐인데
What's wrong with that?
무슨 문제라도 있소?
It's very wrong.
당연히 문제가 있습니다
Because...
그것은...
Because she's my concubine.
이 아이는 제 시첩이기 때문입니다
I don't want others to see her face.
제 여인의 얼굴을 남에게 함부로 보여주고 싶지 않군요
Your Highness, you're young and passionate.
소왕야께서 성정이 다정다감하시니
Just as one would expect of Xuanshanzi's disciple.
과연 사형께서 아끼시는 제자답구려
It's natural for the young to be caught up
젊은 나이에 잠시 남녀의 정에 연연하는 것은
in romance.
자연스러운 일이 아니겠느냐
Since she's Tongzhou's concubine,
내 조카의 시첩이라 하니
please let it go.
사제는 그만 손을 거두게나
Keep a close watch on that Lu guy.
이 노 가 놈을 필히 잘 감시하거라
Don't let anything happen to him.
절대 작은 실수 하나라도 용납지 않을 것이다
It really is you.
역시 네 놈이었구나
Since you used Jiang Lifei as bait,
강려비를 미끼로 삼았으면서
why not trade her for Lu Shanhua?
어찌 그 아이로 노산화를 맞바꾸지 않은 것이냐?
Why go through all this distraction?
기어이 호랑이를 산에서 유인해 내는 계책를 쓰다니
Since you want to see him so badly, let's go.
그토록 보고 싶어 하니, 내 친히 데려가 주지,가자꾸나
Shanhua.
형님
What happened to him?
어찌 된 일입니까?
A vengeful spirit devoured his soul and shattered his heart meridians.
원령에게 혼을 갉아먹혀, 심맥이 모두 끊어졌느니라
If I hadn't been feeding him spirit power,
본좌가 줄곧 영력을 주입해 주지 않았다면
he wouldn't have lasted this long.
오늘까지 버티지도 못했을 터
But his spirit root is already destroyed.
안타깝게도 그의 영근은 이미 파괴되었으니
Feeding him more spirit power won't help.
더는 영력을 불어넣는다 한들 아무런 소용이 없다
Without the fox spirit's power,
여우 요괴의 영력으로 목숨을 잇지 못한다면
he probably won't make it through tonight.
오늘 밤을 넘기기 어려울 것이다
Tonight?
오늘 밤이라니요
Don't you want to rebuild his spirit root
설마 그를 위해 영근을 주조하고
and save him?
다시 생기를 불어넣고 싶지 않다는 말이냐?
You went through all this trouble
이토록 갖은 애를 쓴 이유가
because you're afraid I'll hurt Xiaobangchui.
내가 소봉추를 해칠까 두려워서겠지
Relax. I have no interest in her.
심려 놓거라, 난 그 아이에게 아무런 관심도 없고
And I mean her no harm.
해칠 생각도 없으니
Once the fox spirit is forced out,
여우 요괴를 핍출해 내면
will the host be unharmed?
숙주는 무사한 것입니까?
Of course. It will also rid her of a great danger.
해는커녕, 오히려 그 아이 몸의 커다란 우환을 제거해 주는 셈이지
The fox spirit is a malevolent spirit.
요괴 여우는 본래 흉악한 영물이라
It's been living in her body, waiting for the chance to take over.
인간의 몸에 장기 기생하며 틈을 타 육신을 빼앗으려 할 뿐이다
Extracting the fox spirit
만일 요괴 여우를 밖으로 유인해 낸다면
saves Shanhua
산화의 목숨을 구할 수 있음은 물론이고
and frees Xiaobangchui from that crisis.
그 아이의 위기 역시 풀어줄 수 있느니라
Two birds with one stone.
이토록 일거양득인 일인데
What are you hesitating for?
대체 무엇을 망설이는 게냐?
Shanhua!
형님
Fine.
좋습니다
I'll do it myself.
제가 직접 나서지요
No matter what happens, you're not to touch her.
어떠한 일이 있어도 그 아이에게는 손끝 하나 대지 마십시오
A vengeful spirit devoured his soul and shattered his heart meridians.
원령에게 혼을 갉아먹혀, 심맥이 모두 끊어졌느니라
Without the fox spirit's power,
여우 요괴의 영력으로 목숨을 잇지 못한다면
he probably won't make it through tonight.
오늘 밤을 넘기기 어려울 것이다
This is a forbidden book.
이것은 금서입니다
When you were unconscious,
아직 의식을 회복하지 못하셨을 적
Lifei wanted to take out her inner core to save you.
려비가 내단을 꺼내 공자를 구하려 했습니다
But her cultivation is low, and she's not a spirit creature.
허나 려비는 수행이 아직 얕은 데다 정괴도 아니었으니
She doesn't have one.
어찌 내단이 있었겠습니까
She was desperate to save you.
오직 사람을 구하려는 일념 하나로
She would've given her life.
제 목숨마저 아끼지 않았던 것이지요
A blood-bound covenant initiated by heart's blood.
심혈을 인도 삼아, 손을 맞잡고 맹약을 맺으니
Transfer all injuries from the recipient to the caster.
이 몸을 바쳐, 상대의 상처를 대신 짊어지리라
Transfer all injuries?
상대의 상처를 대신 짊어진다...
Did you find a clue?
혹 무슨 단서라도 찾아낸 것이냐?
I'm warning you, don't do anything on your own.
미리 경고해 두겠는데,이번만큼은 독단적으로 움직여선 안 된다
We're in this together.
이번에는 기필코 생사를 함께 해야 할 것이야
Yeah. We beat Zong Quan together.
옳은 말일세,우리가 함께 힘을 모아 종권을 물리쳤듯
We can handle Zhenyunzi too.
진운자 또한 능히 상대할 수 있을 것이네
As long as the three of us stick together, we'll get it done.
우리 셋이 뜻을 하나로 모은다면 반드시 해낼 수 있을 것이야
You found Lu?
노 오라버니를 찾은 것이야?
I found a secret chamber in Xuanyin Pavilion.
현은각에서 밀실 하나를
But
찾아냈는데
I couldn't break the formation there.
진법을 깨지 못했어
Why didn't you say so?
진작 말했더라면
We can give it a try together.
우리 셋이 함께 시험해 볼 수 있었을 것을
Right.
틀린 말이 아니구려
No time to waste. I'll go prepare now.
일이 시급하니, 내 당장 가서 채비를 하겠소
Careful. Feels like a barrier.
조심하게, 결계가 쳐져 있는 듯싶군
This isn't Xuanyin Pavilion.
이곳은 현은각이 아니야
Where are we?
대체 어디지?
Let's go further in.
앞을 한번 살펴보자구나
It's the Altar of Martyrs.
영렬단이로구나
After the Sea Calamity,
해운이 휩쓸고 간 뒤
Xingzheng Hall enshrined all the fallen elders
성정관에서 전사한 모든 장로와 제자들의 위패를
and disciples here.
모두 이곳에 모셔 두었지
I heard Xuanshanzi mention it before.
전에 백부님께서 말씀하시는 것을 들은 적이 있는데
But because the resentment here is too strong,
이곳은 원기가 너무도 짙어
Xuanshanzi and Zhenyunzi declared it forbidden ground.
백부님과 진운자께서 금지로 정하신 곳이라 하셨는데
How did we end up here?
헌데 우리가 어찌 이곳으로 오게 된 것이지?
And these skulls...?
그렇다면 이 해골들은...
They're demon remains.
마족의 유해야
Did Zhenyunzi hide Lu here?
설마 진운자가 사람을 이곳에 숨겨둔 것인가?
Let's split up and search. Stay alert.
흩어져서 찾아보자구나,모두 조심하고
Lei Xiuyuan, what are you doing?
뇌수원,자네 지금 무엇을 하는 게냐?
Xiuyuan.
수원아
What are you doing?
무엇을 하는 게야?
Sorry. I just want Riyan.
미안하구나, 내게는 오직 일염이 필요할 뿐이야
Xiuyuan, let go!
수원아, 어서 손을 놓거라
Bear with it. It'll be over soon!
조금만 더 참아, 곧 끝날 터이니
Xiuyuan!
수원아
Lei Xiuyuan!
뇌수원
Xiuyuan! Xiuyuan! Let her go!
수원아, 수원아, 제발 그 아이를 놓아주게
Riyan!
일염
Is my spirit power too weak, and the technique incomplete,
정녕 내 영력이 부족하여 술법을 완성하지 못한 탓에
so I could only take on part of her pain?
그 아이의 상처와 고통도 일부만 대신 감당할 수 있는 것인가?
Lifei.
려비야
♪The warmth within my arms♪
♪품 안에 가득했던 그대의 온기♪
♪I can no longer hold on to♪
♪내 이제는 끝내 붙잡지 못하네♪
♪In the cold night, how can I♪
♪시린 이 겨울밤, 그대를 어떻게 다시♪
♪Keep you warm until sunrise?♪
♪동이 틀 때까지 따스히 품어줄까♪
Lifei!
려비야
♪My heartbeat freezes♪
♪가슴은 차갑게 얼어붙고♪
Lifei, let him go!
려비야, 그를 놓거라
I don't want to hurt you.
널 다치게 하고 싶지 않다
I won't! Shut up!
싫어, 입 다물어
♪Looking you in the eyes, I cannot♪
♪그대 눈을 보며 하려던 그 한마디♪
♪Utter that line♪
♪끝내 입 밖으로 내지 못하네♪
Hand me over. You still need to find your master.
차라리 나를 넘겨주거라,너는 네 스승님을 찾아야 하잖느냐
You can't die here.
이런 곳에서 죽어서는 안 되지
Shut up!
입 다물거라
You know Ganhua Realm.
감화의 경지를 아는 것을 보니
You must know my master.
분명 우리 사부님을 아는 것이겠지
And you saved me before. I can't let you die.
더구나 내 목숨을 구해 주었는데,내가 어찌 너를 죽게 두겠느냐?
♪I still linger on♪
♪겹겹이 쌓인 지난날을 놓지 못하네♪
♪Unwilling to let go of every inch of our past♪
♪어젯밤 하늘을 수놓던 아스라한 별빛♪
Lifei.
려비야
Xiuyuan!
수원아
♪But we thought nothing of it♪
♪그때는 어찌 당연하게 여겼을까♪
♪With a heartbroken cry♪
♪가슴이 찢어지는 듯한 애달픈 외침으로♪
♪I wish you well♪
♪오직 그대의 안녕만을 바라네♪
Lifei.
려비야
Lei Xiuyuan,
뇌수원
I won't give up even if it kills me.
난 죽어도 포기하지 않을 것이야
Lifei!
려비야
♪Running relentlessly without regret♪
♪미련 없이 거칠게 발버둥 치는구나♪
♪The storm looms, yet the wind stand in its way♪
♪몰아치는 비바람 온몸으로 막아서며♪
♪A final farewell left on the cliff♪
♪절벽 끝자락에 눈물로 새긴 서약♪
♪I'd shatter my soul♪
♪가슴이 찢어지는 듯한♪
♪To lay all your days in peace♪
♪남은 네 생이 부디 평탄하기를♪
Lifei,
려비야
I won't let you die.
난 결코 널 죽게 두지 않아
♪Pain and wounds cannot be stopped♪
♪밀려드는 고통과 상처를 막을 수 없음을 알면서도♪
♪I will level the seas and mountains♪
♪내 저 산과 바다를 평정하고♪
♪Break the waves, no matter how mad it seems♪
♪풍랑을 부수리니 미쳐 날뛴대도 무엇이 두려우랴♪
♪The storm looms, yet I stand in its way♪
♪닥쳐오는 비바람을 내 기어이 가로막으리♪
♪Torn inside, still I burn bright♪
♪가슴이 무너져 내릴지라도 참으로 감미롭구나♪
♪With the light from my fingertips, I build a paradise♪
♪내 손끝에 맺힌 마지막 빛으로 그대와 함께할 낙원을 세워♪
♪To wander with you♪
♪영원히 그대 곁을 거닐고 싶어라♪
Lifei!
려비야
Zhenyunzi?
진운자
You said you wouldn't touch her!
그 아이는 건드리지 않겠다고 하셨잖습니까
What, just watching breaks your heart?
왜 그러느냐, 그저 지켜보는 것만으로도 그리 가슴이 미어지더냐?
You had been soft
네가 마음약하게 굴며
and refused to hand over the fox spirit.
여우 요괴를 순순히 내놓지 않으니
I might as well take it all by now.
내 직접 한꺼번에 흡수하면 그만이지
Let her go!
그 아이를 놓아주십시오
Lifei.
려비야
Riyan!
임염아
The spirit power of an ancient fox spirit is truly extraordinary.
천년 묵은 여우 요괴의 영력이 과연 대단하구나
I finally have a chance to ascend to immortality!
드디어 내가 신선으로 등선할 날이 머지않았어
Lu.
노 형님
Riyan.
임염아
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설 '천향인' 각색 작품]
♪I trade all the mortal world's splendor♪
♪내 인간 세상의 만장 부귀영화를 쥐고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Our fates intertwined, embracing yet fighting♪
♪얽히고설킨 숙명 속에 서로를 품고 스러지니♪
♪The hardest bond to balance♪
♪이보다 애달픈 연이 어디 있으랴♪
♪Obsessed and struggling, a thousand thoughts arise♪
♪집착 속에 아파하며 온갖 마음을 내어 보아도♪
♪Love sprouts again in this lifetime♪
♪이번 생의 애달픈사랑은 다시 움트네♪
♪No calamity can rival the lingering thread of a fragrance♪
♪수많은 겁난을 겪어도  한 줄기 향기를 향한 미련은 떨치지 못하네♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너♪
♪Past the pagoda, in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪부도탑을 지나 비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들 어떠하리♪
♪With you, we melt into mist and haze♪
♪기꺼이 그대와 함께 환영으로 화하리라♪
♪I trade the highest heaven and endless clouds♪
♪내 구만장천의 붉은 노을을 딛고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Pierced by countless arrows, pain and illness pile on♪
♪만 개의 화살이 심장을 꿰뚫는 고통이 밀려와도♪
♪Yet I remain silent♪
♪그저 묵묵히 소리 없이 삼키네♪
♪Deep love and long yearning, a kiss falls into a dream♪
♪깊어가는 정과 그리움은 꿈결 속에 내려앉고♪
♪In the distant night, bitterness blooms♪
♪외롭고 긴 밤하늘 아래 쓰라린 꽃이 피어나네♪
♪The grand chapter is rewritten, startling the whole world♪
♪찬란한 운명을 다시 쓰니 온 세상이 경탄하누나♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너♪
♪Past the pagoda, in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪부도탑을 지나 비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들 어떠하리♪
♪If the seal can't be broken, then let it go♪
♪얽매인 봉인을 풀 수 없다면차라리 내려놓으리♪
♪Where the heart finds peace, there is home♪
♪이 내 마음 편히 쉴 곳이 곧 나의 집이어라♪
♪Side by side, we fly through seas of clouds♪
♪비익조가 되어 구름 바다를 가로지르고♪
♪Break through the waves, the heart's ocean knows no shore♪
♪거친 파도를 깨부수니 마음의 바다는 끝이 없어라♪
♪Always, at the very end of fate♪
♪언제나 가혹한숙명의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of defiance♪
♪끝까지 모질게 버텨내던 그 순간♪
♪In the human world or above, like flowing water and falling petals♪
♪천상과 인간 세상사 모두 흐르는 물과 지는 꽃 같으니♪
♪Let this fleeting life be whatever it may♪
♪덧없는 이 허무한 삶을 그저 순리에 맡기리라♪